[MUSIC PLAYING]
[播放音乐]
ROB DODSON: Hey, everyone.
罗布·多德森：大家好
What's up?
最近如何？
It's Rob Dodson.
我是罗布·多德森
Today is a very special episode of Polycasts
今天是Polycasts系列教程中 特殊的一课
because Polymer 0.8 is finally upon us,
因为Polymer0.8终于上线了
so I'm going to be showing you how to create
所以我将向你展示如何创建
your own elements with it.
自己的元素
Let's dive in.
好的我们开始吧
So this is what I'm going to build today.
这就是我今天要创建的
It's a very simple alert banner.
一个非常简洁的提示横幅
It's the kind of thing you might see
当用户完成了某个动作
after a user completes an action or receives
或者接收到了某种通知后
a notification of some kind.
就会弹出这个提示
In the creating element, you're going to need three things.
为了创建一个元素 你需要三样东西
You need the web components polyfills,
您需Web组件polyfills
and these ensure that your element shows up
它能保证你的元素
in different browsers.
能在不同浏览器中显示
You're going to need Polymer itself.
你还需要Polymer本身
And lastly, you're going to need a separate HTML file to hold
最后 你需要一个单独的HTML文件来保存
your elements definition.
你的元素定义
Now, registering a tag in Polymer 0.8 is pretty easy.
在Polymer0.8中 注册一个标签是很容易的
You call the Polymer constructor,
首先调用Polymer构造器
you pass in an object with an "is" property,
传入一个包含is属性的对象
and then you give it a tag name.
然后给它一个标签名就可以了
It's really important that your tag include a dash in the name.
重要的是 你的标签名中 必须包含破折号
What this does is it signifies to the browser, hey,
这样做是为了告诉浏览器
I'm creating a custom element here.
嘿 我正在创建一个自定义元素
You need to make sure to treat it kind of special.
你得特殊对待它
And once you've got all of this in place, ta-da!
当这一切就位 当当！
You've just created your own HTML tag.
你成功创建了 属于你自己的HTML标签
Now, you could just start using this new tag,
现在 你可以开始使用 这个新的标签了
but it's a little boring because it doesn't actually display
但它现在比较无聊 因为它实际上
anything, so let's change that.
并不能显示任何东西 所以我们来做些修改
To render content inside of an element,
为了渲染元素中的内容
you're going to need to include a DOM module tag
你需要引入一个 包含template的
with a template inside of it.
DOM模块标签
You can think of this kind of like the old Polymer element
你可能会觉得它和 旧版的Polymer元素很像
if you've worked with previous versions.
如果你使用过以前的版本
It's important to make sure you give your DOM module an ID that
这里重要的一点是 确保给你的DOM设置的ID
matches your tag name, and what this
和你的标签名称相匹配
does is it helps Polymer find your content so it knows what
它能帮助Polymer定位你的内容
to render.
从而知道它要渲染什么
Inside of this template, I can include really whatever I want.
我可以在template里面 包含任何我想要的元素
I can drop in a div with an alert message.
比如我可以添加一个 包含提示信息的div元素
But what I want to do is actually take this up a notch.
但我想要做的 比这个要高一个档次
I want to let the user pass in the message for my alert.
我想让我的alert 能接受用户传入的消息
So instead of hard coding some text in there,
因此 我将不硬编码一些文字
I'm going to include another element called a content tag.
而是添加另一个 叫做content的元素标签
I've talked about content tags in a previous episode.
我在以前的视频教程里 谈到过content标签
You can catch this video down here
如果你想了解更多
if you want to learn a little bit more about them.
你可以在下面这里 找到这个视频
In short, they let content from the lite DOM
总之 他们能把 精简版DOM里的content元素
get projected and rendered inside of my element.
映射到我的元素里 并通过我的元素进行渲染
OK, I think I've talked enough at this point.
好的 关于这一点我 已经说的够多了
I'm sure you're ready to go, so let's hop into our code editor
我敢肯定你已经跃跃欲试了 让我们跳转到代码编辑器
and get hacking.
开始写点代码吧
So over my bower.json, I've got two dependencies listed here.
在我的bower.json文件里 添加了两个依赖
I've got webcomponents.js, which is pointing at version 0.6,
一个是webcomponentsjs 指向0.6版本
and I've got polymer, which right now I'm
另一个是Polymer
pointing at the 0.8 preview branch,
当前指向的是0.8-preview版本
and that's because at the time of this recording,
这是因为在我录制视频的时候
0.8 isn't even out yet.
0.8版本没有发布呢
But if you check the Polymer site
但是如果你查看Polymer网站
and it looks like 0.8 has landed,
发现0.8版本已经发布
then you're good to go ahead and change this
那么你完全可以更进一步
to the actual 0.8 tag.
把它修改成0.8版本的标签
Then I'm going to hop over to my terminal,
接着跳转到终端
and I'm going to run bower install.
运行bower install
This will pull down all of those dependencies.
这会自动下载所有依赖库
And this one I'm pretty much ready to rock,
现在一切准备就绪
so in my index.html file, I'm going
在我的index.html文件中
to first include the polyfills for webcomponents.js.
首先引入webcomponents.js的 polyfills
Now, you'll notice here that I'm using webcomponents-lite.js.
你会发现我在此使用 webcomponents-lite.js
webcomponents-lite.js is all the web components' polyfills minus
等于所有Web组件的polyfills
the Shadow DOM polyfill.
减去Shadow DOM的polyfill
The reason I'm doing this is because Polymer 0.8 includes
我这样做的原因是 Polymer 0.8中自带了
its own much more performant variation of the Shadow DOM
性能更好的Shadow DOM的变体
polyfill, which is called Shady DOM.
叫做Shady DOM
Now I'm going to talk about Shady DOM a bunch in a future
我会在未来的视频中 详细讲解Shady DOM
episode, but for now if you just want to get rolling,
但现在 如果你只是想跟着教程 了解个大概的话
you can just include webcomponents-lite.js,
引入webcomponents-lite.js即可
and you should be good to go.
这不会对你有什么影响
Next I'm going to create an HTML file called quick-alert.html,
接着我要创建一个 名为quick-alert.html的HTML文件
and this is where I'm going to define my elements definition.
我将在这里对我的元素进行定义
So I'm going to include an import for Polymer that
首先我需要引入Polymer
ensures the Polymer has been loaded before I
确保在我注册自己的标签前
try to register my tag.
已经加载了Polymer
And then I'm going to drop in a DOM module
然后 我要添加一个DOM模块元素
element and a template.
以及一个template元素
Lastly, I've got to give my DOM module an ID which
最后 我得给我的DOM模块设置个ID
matches my element's name.
它应该和元素名称相对应
Inside this template, I can create whatever sort of content
在template里 我可以创建任何类型的内容
I want, so I'm going to drop in an alert message,
这里我需要添加一个提示信息
and I'm also going to include some CSS styles.
并添加一些CSS样式
Now, you may have not seen this host selector before.
你可能没见过这个host选择器
That might be new for you.
这对你来说可能比较新鲜
So the host selector is actually something
host选择器实际上是
that was added by the Shadow DOM CSS spec, and what it does
Shadow DOM的CSS补充的
is it allows an element to refer to itself.
它允许一个元素引用自身
It basically allows this quick-alert tag
在此它让quick-alert标签
to tell the browser, hey, this is how I should be rendered.
告诉浏览器 嘿 这里是我期待的渲染方式
And you can include other things inside of your style block
在style标签块里 如果你愿意
if you want.
你还可以包含其他东西
I've got an alert class here, which is referring to my div
这里我添加了一个alert类
down here.
它指向这里的div
That works, as well.
这样也可以
The last thing I'm going to do is include a script tag
最后一件事是引入script标签
and kick off the Polymer constructor
调用Polymer构造器
and pass in my tag name.
并传入我的标签名
Now, over in my index.html, I'm going
回到我的index.html
to import the definition for my quick-alert element.
我需要导入我的 quick-alert元素的定义
And then I'm just going to use the tag on my page.
然后我就可以在我的页面上 使用这个标签了
Hop over to Chrome, and you can see that the new tag is
切换到Chrome 你可以看到
rendering just as we expected.
新标签的渲染 正如我们所预期的一样
So the last thing we need to do is pass in a content element
我们要做的最后一件事是 传入一个content元素
so that the user can hand off any message they want.
这样用户就可以切换 任何他们想要的消息
So back in my elements definition,
回到我的元素定义
I'm going to replace this hard-coded text with a content
我要用content元素
element.
来代替这里的硬编码文本
And now in my index file, I can pass whatever message
现在在我的index文件中 我可以传递任何消息
I want into the quick-alert tag, and that's
给我的quick-alert标签
what's actually going to render when I hop over to Chrome
当我切换回Chrome浏览器 查看效果的时候
and check it out in my browser.
渲染的内容就是这些消息
And there you have it-- your very first element
至此全部完成了 Polymer 0.8里的
in Polymer 0.8.
你的第一个自定义元素
Now, we have just barely scratched the surface
到这里为止
of what is in this new release.
我们只是看了看新版本的皮毛
So in the upcoming episodes, I'm going
在接下来的几个视频里
to be looking at more of the features in 0.8.
我会把重点放在 介绍0.8版本的新特性上
Be sure to subscribe if you want to catch those videos
如果你想要在第一时间 看到那些视频
as they're rolling out.
记得订阅我们的节目
Also be sure to join our G+ community if you want to show
除此之外
off some of the things that you're working on or if you
如果你想要分享你正在做的 或者你想把你的成果
just want to hand out with yours truly on the internet.
放到真实的网络环境里 记得加入我们的G+社区
As always, thank you so much for watching,
与往常一样 感谢你的观看
and I will see you next time.
我们下次再见
[CLANKING SOUND]
[叮当作响的声音]
CAMERAMAN: That's it, Rob.
摄影：就这样 罗布
ROB DODSON: I thought you said "bone silence,"
罗布·多德森：我以为你说“骨头沉默”
and then I thought that was a really cool band name.
然后我觉得这是一个 非常酷的乐队的名字
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[播放音乐]